A task lands in Codex. HQ treats it like a project, not a chat reply.
HQ assigns roles, ownership, and review responsibility before work starts.
The agents challenge the plan. Weak shortcuts are rejected early.
Memory opens first, so old failures are not repeated.
Work moves through visible states: planned, building, blocked, validating, and reviewed.
The build produces files, demos, docs, and validation checks.
Risky actions stop at deferred gates until a human approves.
Telegram becomes the ops console: approve, reject, pause, retry, status, and logs.
Validation happens before confidence. Evidence beats vibes.
Telemetry records what worked, what failed, and what the next session should remember.
Agent HQ OS connects memory, agents, queues, gates, Telegram control, validation, and telemetry.